Guide to the William Kent Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Upon graduation became engaged in the management of his father's estate as member of firm of A. E. Kent & Son; in 1903 entered into partnership with his classmate, Edward L. Burke, under name of Kent & Burke (later Kent & Burke Company), dealers in live stock, grain, and land (in Genoa, Nebr., until 1012 and since then in Omaha), and remained in that connection until his death, becoming president of the company upon the death of Mr. Burke in 1926; president of Golconda (Nev.) Cattle Company 1895-1920; director of American Trust & Savings Bank of Chicago 1890-1907 of Genoa National Bank 1904-1915, and of International Company (mining) since 1902; member Chicago City Council 1895-1897; president of Municipal Voters'. League 1898-1900 (a founder of the league in 1897 and member of executive committee 1897-1904); vice-president of the Old Age Pension Association; had lived in California since 1907; represented 2d District of California in 62d Congress (1911-1913) and reelected as an Independent to 63d and 64th Congresses for the new 1st District; member U. S. Tariff Commission 1917-1921; resigned to become candidate for senator from California (defeated for nomination); honorary M.A. 1908; elected a governor of Yale Publishing Association in 1925, for a four year term; in 1924 appointed by Governor Pinchot of Pennsylvania member of Giant Power Advisory Board, which was formed to pass on final report of Giant Power Survey before it was submitted to Pennsylvania Legislature; donor of three hundred acres of land on Mount Tamalpais to the United States Government as a national monument to be known as the Muir Woods; vice-president of National Parks Association (representing California) since 1920; author: Practical Politics, A Lay Sermon (1896); had contributed numerous articles on politics to Yale Review, Survey, American Magazine, Collier's Weekly; and other magazines; member American Economic Association, National Municipal League, Civil Service Reform League, and Illinois Civil Service Association; trustee of All Souls' Church (undenominational), Chicago 1891-1895; donor with his father in 1885 of Kent Hall, Yale University (known as Kent Chemical Laboratory until 1922).
Married February 23, 1890, in Ojai Valley, Calif., Elizabeth, daughter of Thomas Anthony Thacher (B.A. 1835, LL.D. Western Reserve 1869), assistant professor and professor of the Latin language and literature at Yale 1838-1886, and Elizabeth Baldwin (Sherman) Thacher, granddaughter of Roger Sherman (B.A. 1787), great-granddaughter of Roger Sherman (honorary M.A. 1768), treasurer of Yale 1754-1776 and a signer of the Declaration of Independence, a sister of Sherman D. Thacher, '83, and William L. Thacher, '87, and half sister of James K. Thacher, '68, Thomas Thacher, '71, Edward S. Thacher, '72, Alfred B. Thacher, '74, and John S. Thacher, '77. Children: Albert Emmett, '13; Thomas Thacher, '15; William, Jr., '17; Elizabeth Sherman, the wife of G. Stanleigh Arnold, '03; Adaline Dutton (B.A. Vassar 1923); Sherman, '26; and Roger, '28.
Death due to pneumonia. His ashes lie in California. Survived by wife, five sons, two daughters, and ten grandchildren.
Yale College Obituary Record, 1927-1928. pp. 106-108.
American Magazine; Conservation of natural resources; Environmental protection; Families; Government ownership; Meat industry and trade; National parks and reserves; Peace; Progressivism (United States politics); Public lands; Rangelands; Tariff; Water -- Law and legislation; Women's rights; World War, 1939-1945; California -- Politics and government; Chicago (Ill.) -- Politics and government; East Asia -- Foreign relations -- United States; Hetch Hetchy Valley (Calif.); Marin County (Calif.); Middle West; San Francisco (Calif.); Tahoe, Lake (Calif. and Nev.); United States -- Foreign relations -- East Asia; United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1953; United States -- Race relations; West (U.S.); Scrapbooks; Legislators; Politicians; Addams, Jane, 1860-1935; Arnold, George Stanleigh, 1881-1942; Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946; Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940; Boyden, William C.; Brandeis, Louis Dembitz, 1856-1941; Burke, Edward Lathrop, 1864-1926; Camp, Walter, 1859-1925; Denman, William, 1872-1959; Dunne, Finley Peter, 1867-1936; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969; Farrington, Wallace R. (Wallace Rider), 1871-1933; Fisher, Walter L. (Walter Lowrie), 1862-1935; Gilson, Garland; Hapgood, Norman, 1868-1937; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923; Heney, Francis Joseph, 1859-1937; Hichborn, Franklin, 1869-1963; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; House, Edward Mandell, 1858-1938; Howe, Frederic C., 1867-1940; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952; Johnson, Hiram, 1866-1945; Jones, Jenkin Lloyd, 1843-1918; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931; Kent, Albert Emmet, 1830-1901; Kent, Elizabeth Thacher, 1868-1952; Kent, Roger, 1906-1980; Kent, Sherman; Kent, William, 1864-1928; King, Judson, 1872-1958; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1855-1925; Lane, Franklin K.; Lathrop, Julia Clifford, 1858-1932; Lenroot, Irvine Luther, 1869-1949; Lloyd, Henry Demarest, 1847-1903; McAdoo, W. G. (William Gibbs), 1863-1941; McClatchy, Charles K., 1858-1936; Mead, Elwood, 1858-1936; Muir, John, 1838-1914; Norris, George W. (George William), 1861-1944; Older, Fremont, 1856-1935; Phelan, James D. (James Duval), 1861-1930; Phillips, John S. (John Sanburn), 1861-1949; Pinchot, Amos, 1873-1944; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946; Post, Louis F. (Louis Freeland), 1849-1928; Rogers, James Gamble, 1867-1947; Rogers, John, 1866-1939; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Rowell, Chester H. (Chester Harvey), 1867-1948; Sherman, Roger, 1768-1856; Steffens, Lincoln, 1866-1936; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Tarbell, Ida M. (Ida Minerva), 1857-1944; Taussig, F. W. (Frank William), 1859-1940; Taylor, Graham, 1851-1938; Thacher, Thomas Anthony, 1815-1886; Thompson, Rolfe L.; U'Ren, Milton T.; Wald, Lillian D., 1867-1940; Washburn, William D. (William Drew), 1863-1929; West, George P.; White, Stewart Edward, 1873-1946; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; United States. Congress. House; United States. National Park Service; All Souls Church (Chicago, Ill.); Golconda Cattle Company; Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League; National Popular Government League; National Woman's Party; Thacher School (Ojai, Calif.); United States Tariff Commission; Women's International League for Peace and Freedom; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1887; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1801-1961, undated; Series I; 22.50' (54 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence arranged in chronological order.
  - 1801-1886 (Box 1, Folder 1-12)
  - 1887-1905 (Box 2, Folder 13-30)
  - 1906-1908 June (Box 3, Folder 31-55)
  - 1908 July-1909 May (Box 4, Folder 56-73)
  - 1909 June-December (Box 5, Folder 74-90)
  - 1909 (no month)-1910 April (Box 6, Folder 91-108)
  - 1910 May-July (Box 7, Folder 109-124)
  - 1910 August-November 11 (Box 8, Folder 125-140)
  - 1910 November 12-1911 April 16 (Box 9, Folder 141-159)
  - 1911 April 17-August (Box 10, Folder 160-180)
  - 1911 September-1912 January 23 (Box 11, Folder 181-202)
  - 1912 January 24-May (Box 12, Folder 203-223)
  - 1912 June-October (Box 13, Folder 224-247)
  - 1912 November-1913 February 8 (Box 14, Folder 248-267)
  - 1913 February 9-May 9 (Box 15, Folder 268-290)
  - 1913 May 10-July (Box 16, Folder 291-312)
  - 1913 August-November 17 (Box 17, Folder 313-338)
  - 1913 November 18-1914 March (Box 18, Folder 339-356)
  - 1914 April-July 17 (Box 19, Folder 357-378)
  - 1914 July 18-1915 January (Box 20, Folder 379-401)
  - 1915 February-July 25 (Box 21, Folder 402-427)
  - 1915 July 26-December (Box 22, Folder 428-448)
  - 1916 January-March 10 (Box 23, Folder 449-467)
  - 1916 March 11-June 15 (Box 24, Folder 468-487)
  - 1916 June 16 - December 20 (Box 25, Folder 488-508)
  - 1916 December 21 - 1917 September 30 (Box 26, Folder 509-526)
  - 1917 October - 1918 May 19 (Box 27, Folder 527-548)
  - 1918 May 20 - November (Box 28, Folder 549-567)
  - 1918 December - 1919 July (Box 29, Folder 568-591)
  - 1919 August - 1920 January (Box 30, Folder 592-613)
  - 1920 February - June (Box 31, Folder 614-633)
  - 1920 July - 1921 February (Box 32, Folder 634-656)
  - 1921 March - July 15 (Box 33, Folder 657-680)
  - 1921 July 16 - September (Box 34, Folder 681-698)
  - 1921 October - 1922 February (Box 35, Folder 699-721)
  - 1922 March - June (Box 36, Folder 722-741)
  - 1922 July - December (Box 37, Folder 742-762)
  - 1923 January - April (Box 38, Folder 763-782)
  - 1923 May - 1924 January 22 (Box 39, Folder 783-804)
  - 1924 January 23 - May (Box 40, Folder 805-825)
  - 1924 June - November (Box 41, Folder 826-844)
  - 1924 December - 1925 April (Box 42, Folder 845-862)
  - 1925 May - November (Box 43, Folder 863-880)
  - 1925 December - 1926 August (Box 44, Folder 881-901)
  - 1926 September - 1927 February (Box 45, Folder 902-921)
  - 1927 March - December (Box 46, Folder 922-939)
  - 1928 January - 1932 May (Box 47, Folder 940-960)
  - 1932 June - 1936 December (Box 48, Folder 961-976)
  - 1937 - 1940 (Box 49, Folder 977-994)
  - 1941 January - 1943 November (Box 50, Folder 995-1009)
  - 1943 December - 1947 (Box 51, Folder 1010-1028)
  - 1948 - 1951 August 15 (Box 52, Folder 1029-1045)
  - 1951 August 16 - 1952, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 1046-1050)
  - Undated (Box 53, Folder 1046-1050)
  - Howard, Adaline Kent (Box 53, Folder 1051)
  - Kent, Albert E. (1890-1933) (Box 53, Folder 1052-1053)
  - Kent, William, Jr. (Box 53, Folder 1054)
  - Kent, Roger (Box 53, Folder 1055)
  - Kent, Thomas (Box 53, Folder 1056)
  - Arnold, Elizabeth Kent (Box 54, Folder 1057)
  - Kent, Sherman and Elizabeth (Box 54, Folder 1058)
  - Non-family (Box 54, Folder 1059)
  - Kent, William (Box 54, Folder 1060)
  - Kent grandchildren (Box 54, Folder 1061)
  - Thacher, Elizabeth Baldwin Sherman (Box 54, Folder 1062)
  - Kent, Elizabeth Thacher (Box 54, Folder 1063)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 54, Folder 1064)
  - Kent, Alice Cooke (Box 54, Folder 1065)
  - Arnold, Evelyn (Box 54, Folder 1066)
  - Kent, Albert E. (1830-1901) and Adaline Dutton (Box 54, Folder 1067)
- WRITINGS, 1873-1929, undated; Series II; 2.50' (6 boxes)
  This series is arranged in two sections: General and Scrapbooks. Both files are arranged alphabetically by title or topic. Miscellaneous material is filed at the end of each section.
  - General
    - "Abrogation of Russian Treaty", 1911 December (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - "Jane Addams", [ca. 1905] (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - "Jane Addams", 1899 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - "For the Proposed Alien Land Law", 1920 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - "The American City Electorate", undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - "Animile Poems", [ca. 1921] (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - "Apaches", n. d. (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - "The Arbitration Treaties", 1911 August (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Autobiographical, undated (Box 55, Folder 9)
      General note
      See also: box 56, folder 46
    - Ballinger-Pinchot, [ca. 1910] (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - "The Bankers' Resolutions Concerning the Water and Power Act", 1922 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - "Banking and Currency Bill", 1913 September (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - "Battleships", 1912 August (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - "Behind the Smile", [1909?] (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - "Boyhood Recollections of Marin, County, Reminiscences of Outdoor Life", 1929 (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - "California Delegation Lie Party", 1912 (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - "William Kent Shows the California Water and Power Act to be a Water Conservation Measure", 1924 (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Campaign statements, 1914 (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - "A Christmas Outline", undated (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - "Cities and Things", 1909 May (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - Civic Federation, 1894 November (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - "Clan Loyalty and the G.O.P.", 1924 November (Box 55, Folder 21)
    - Commonwealth Club address, 1920 July (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - Concerning: Certain Economic and Social Phases of Immigration", 1912 Dec, 1914 February (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - "Concerning Congressmen", undated (Box 55, Folder 24)
    - "Concerning the Production and Distribution of Wealth under a Protective Tariff", 1911 April (Box 55, Folder 25)
    - "Concerning the European War", 1914 August (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - "End of the War Never to Come", 1915 October (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - "Concerning Woman Suffrage - From a Man's Viewpoint", 1913 August (Box 55, Folder 27)
    - Congressional bills and speeches, 1911-1917 (Box 55, Folder 28)
    - Conservation in Southern Marin, 1913 (Box 55, Folder 29)
    - Coolidge and scandals, 1924 March (Box 55, Folder 30)
    - Cooperative movement, undated (Box 55, Folder 31)
    - Dedication of the Sidney B. Cushing Cushing Theatre, 1915 June (Box 55, Folder 32)
    - Charles Deems dinner, 1922 June (Box 55, Folder 33)
    - "Some Essentials of Democratic Life on the Farm,", undated (Box 55, Folder 34)
    - "Democracy and Efficiency", 1912 March (Box 55, Folder 35)
    - "Denys. A Study from 'The Cloister and the Hearth'", 1904 December (Box 56, Folder 36)
    - Digger Indians, undated (Box 56, Folder 37)
    - "Dr. Fairfax: A Sketch", undated (Box 56, Folder 38)
    - Economic issues, 1920 August (Box 56, Folder 39)
    - "Economics Under Democracy", 1920 March (Box 56, Folder 40)
    - "Eight Years of Carter Harrison, 1905 March (Box 56, Folder 41)
    - "Equal Suffrage Amendment", 1915 January (Box 56, Folder 42)
    - "A Farmer's. Prayer", 1905 (Box 56, Folder 43)
    - "Federal Control of Water Power", 1914 July (Box 56, Folder 44)
    - "Federal Trades Commission - Borland Amendment Asking $400,000 in Consonance with President's Letter", 1917 February (Box 56, Folder 45)
    - "Field notes of an Impractical Politician", undated (Box 56, Folder 46)
      See also: box 1, folder 9
    - Walter Fisher, 1911 (Box 56, Folder 47)
    - "Flag - Petaluma", 1910 June (Box 56, Folder 48)
    - "For Love Is All", undated (Box 56, Folder 49)
    - Four Power Pact, 1922 March (Box 56, Folder 50)
    - Free government, 1919 August (Box 56, Folder 51)
    - Free List Bill, undated (Box 56, Folder 52)
    - Free zones, 1917 October (Box 56, Folder 53)
    - Freemont Older, undated (Box 56, Folder 54)
    - "From a Nevada Ranch", undated (Box 56, Folder 55)
    - "From the Old Country", 1891 May (Box 56, Folder 56)
    - "Future of Business as affected by the War", 1918 January (Box 56, Folder 57)
    - "Gambling San Rafael", undated (Box 56, Folder 58)
    - "A Gentleman Ranchman", undated (Box 56, Folder 59)
    - "George Washington", 1898 (Box 56, Folder 60)
    - "Getting Man Back on the Land", 1918 December (Box 56, Folder 61)
    - "Good Roads", 1914 February (Box 56, Folder 62)
    - Government use of resources, undated (Box 56, Folder 63)
    - Great leadership, 1923 October (Box 56, Folder 64)
    - "Harlan the Man", 1905 January (Box 56, Folder 65)
    - Hawaii, undated (Box 56, Folder 66)
    - Heney banquet, 1910 November (Box 56, Folder 67)
    - "Here's Hoping", 1906 March (Box 56, Folder 68)
    - Hetch Hetchy, 1913 Sep, 1922 May (Box 56, Folder 69)
    - Washington conference on the High Cost of Living, 1917 July (Box 56, Folder 70)
      See also: box 59, folder 170
    - High prices to consumers and low prices to producers of beans and other feed products, 1919 October (Box 56, Folder 71)
    - "Hobson Prohibition Amendment", 1914 December (Box 56, Folder 72)
    - "Hunting Sketches", undated (Box 56, Folder 73)
    - "I'm Scared", undated (Box 56, Folder 74)
    - "In the Matter of the Packers", 1918 April (Box 56, Folder 75)
    - "The Independent Movement in City Government", 1907 February (Box 56, Folder 76)
    - "The Influence of Coleridge on English Thought", [1886] (Box 56, Folder 77)
    - "Interstate Control of the Tuberculosis Problem", undated (Box 56, Folder 78)
    - "An Introductory Address," Yale Alumni meeting, 1917 June (Box 56, Folder 79)
    - "It", undated (Box 56, Folder 80)
    - "Johnson of California", 1912 February (Box 56, Folder 81)
    - "Jenkin Lloyd Jones", 1910 (Box 56, Folder 82)
    - "A Tribute", 1918 November (Box 56, Folder 82)
    - "A Jonesburg View of the Markets", undated (Box 56, Folder 83)
    - "Labor Day", undated (Box 57, Folder 84)
    - LaFollette, 1924 September (Box 57, Folder 85)
    - "Land Tenure and Public Policy", 1918 December (Box 57, Folder 86)
    - Last Congress, 1913 November (Box 57, Folder 87)
    - League of Nations and the Treaty of Versailles, 1919 Feb, Mar, 1921 December (Box 57, Folder 88)
    - "What Should be the Legal Qualifications of Voters In America", undated (Box 57, Folder 89)
    - "Lessons from the Earthquake", 1906 May (Box 57, Folder 90)
    - "A Letter That Never Was Sent", 1909 May (Box 57, Folder 91)
    - "Lower California", undated (Box 57, Folder 92)
    - "A Man is Known by the Company He Keeps", 1907 April (Box 57, Folder 93)
      See also: box 59, folder 181
    - "Marking off a Tamelpais Park", 1915 May (Box 57, Folder 94)
    - "Me and Doe", 1904 January (Box 57, Folder 95)
    - "Adventures in Mexico", undated (Box 57, Folder 96)
    - "Mississippi", undated (Box 57, Folder 97)
    - "The Monroe Doctrine: An Obsolete Shibboleth", 1913 July (Box 57, Folder 98)
    - "Mountain Park", undated (Box 57, Folder 99)
    - "The Mountains of Mendocino", undated (Box 57, Folder 100)
    - "Municipal Citizenship", 1905 February (Box 57, Folder 101)
    - City Club Civic Associations' Night, 1912 June (Box 57, Folder 102)
    - National Popular Government League - Reconstruction Conference and Luncheon Forums, 1919 January - June (Box 57, Folder 103)
    - "Suspension of Naval Construction Program", 1913 December (Box 57, Folder 104)
    - "Railroads in Alaska", 1914 February (Box 57, Folder 104)
    - "The Woman's Eight-Hour Law", 1914 February (Box 57, Folder 104)
    - "Nebraska", 1925 April (Box 57, Folder 105)
    - "The Need and the Advent of a City Electorate", 1906 October (Box 57, Folder 106)
    - "Need and Waste", 1910 May (Box 57, Folder 107)
    - "New Mexico", undated (Box 57, Folder 108)
    - Non-Partisan League - St. Paul, 1918 March (Box 57, Folder 109)
    - "Notes on Cicero's Commonwealth ", 1903 January (Box 57, Folder 110)
    - "Notes on Impromptu Yale Talk", 1915 July (Box 57, Folder 111)
    - Board of Supervisors Association of California address, 1920 April (Box 57, Folder 112)
    - Oriental exclusion, 1910, 1913, 1920, undated (Box 57, Folder 113)
    - Ovid, undated (Box 57, Folder 114)
    - "On Traction Ordinance", 1907 March (Box 57, Folder 115)
    - "The One and the Universe", 1892 April (Box 57, Folder 116)
    - "Opportunity - Three Views", 1906 June (Box 57, Folder 117)
    - "Our Gossip", undated (Box 57, Folder 118)
    - "Out Doors", undated (Box 57, Folder 119)
    - "Outline Chicago Traction", [1908 May] (Box 57, Folder 120)
    - "The Panama Canal Tolls", 1912 May (Box 58, Folder 121)
    - Patriotism, undated (Box 58, Folder 122)
    - Philpot golden wedding anniversary, 1903 (Box 58, Folder 123)
    - Poetry, 1873-1915, undated (Box 58, Folder 124)
    - "Political Police", 1907 February (Box 58, Folder 125)
    - "A Political Survey", 1905 March (Box 58, Folder 126)
    - "Politics and Politicians", undated (Box 58, Folder 127)
    - "Postal Regulations and Parcel Post", 1912 April (Box 58, Folder 128)
    - "Practical Politics", 1896 September (Box 58, Folder 129)
    - Preparedness, 1915 Feb, 1916 Jan, Feb, undated (Box 58, Folder 130)
    - "The Primary a Safeguard for Democracy", 1924 April (Box 58, Folder 131)
    - "Privilege and Interference", 1909 October (Box 58, Folder 132)
    - "A Problem", undated (Box 58, Folder 133)
    - "The Problem of Dealing with Vice in Great Cities", 1901 January (Box 58, Folder 134)
    - Procession of years, undated (Box 58, Folder 135)
    - "The Proper Relation between Literacy and Colloquial Languages", undated (Box 58, Folder 136)
    - Public lands for cattle and sheep in Nevada and Nebraska, [ca. 1917] (Box 58, Folder 137)
    - Public ownership and railroads, 1920 August (Box 58, Folder 138)
    - Public water power, undated (Box 58, Folder 139)
    - Publication of campaign expenses, 1914 June (Box 58, Folder 140)
    - "Publicity as a Factor in Republican Government", 1901 October (Box 58, Folder 141)
    - "A Rear View", undated (Box 58, Folder 142)
    - "The Recent Administration", 1913 October (Box 58, Folder 143)
    - Reciprocity, undated (Box 58, Folder 144)
    - "The Redwoods", undated (Box 58, Folder 145)
    - Remarks at the College Women's Club, 1918 February (Box 58, Folder 146)
    - "Water-Power Bills", 1916 June (Box 58, Folder 147)
    - "The Reporter…", undated (Box 58, Folder 148)
    - "Res Indigestae: A Cyclopaedia of Universal Ignorance", 1905 November (Box 58, Folder 149)
    - "Roosevelt as Related to the People and a Third Term", 1909 December (Box 58, Folder 150)
    - "Rural Recreation", 1911 May (Box 58, Folder 151)
    - "Sallust and the Revellers", 1892 November (Box 58, Folder 152)
    - "The Salvation Army: A Solicitation for Help", 1919 May (Box 58, Folder 153)
    - San Francisco Advertising Club luncheon, 1919 December (Box 58, Folder 154)
    - "Report on the Causes of Municipal Corruption in San Francisco", 1910 January (Box 58, Folder 155)
    - "San Francisco Letter", 1909. December (Box 58, Folder 156)
    - "Notes on the San Francisco Mint", undated (Box 58, Folder 157)
    - "San Francisco's Traction Query - Chicago's Answer.", undated (Box 58, Folder 158)
    - "The Seamen's Bill", 1912 July (Box 58, Folder 159)
    - "Shake! Personal Reminiscences of San Francisco", 1906 November (Box 58, Folder 160)
    - "The Sheep, Shorn of all Poesy", undated (Box 58, Folder 161)
    - "The Sherwood Pension Bill", 1911 December (Box 58, Folder 162)
    - "Sketch of Casaubon", undated (Box 59, Folder 163)
    - "Social Economics", 1909 December (Box 59, Folder 164)
    - "Some Essentials of Democratic Govt.", undated (Box 59, Folder 165)
    - "Some Reminiscences of Hiram Johnson", 1922 July (Box 59, Folder 166)
    - "Southern Marin", 1910 April (Box 59, Folder 167)
    - "Southern Marin", 1922 April (Box 59, Folder 167)
    - Southern Pacific, undated (Box 59, Folder 168)
    - Optimists Club luncheon, 1920 February (Box 59, Folder 169)
    - "Speech at the Washington Conference on the High Cost of Living", 1917 July (Box 59, Folder 170)
      See also: box 59, folder 70
    - Municipal Voters League dinner, undated (Box 59, Folder 171)
    - "Spooking Bostonward", undated (Box 59, Folder 172)
    - "Notes of talk to the student body of the Junior College", 1927 February (Box 59, Folder 173)
    - Old Settler's meetings, 1914 October, 1923 October (Box 59, Folder 174)
    - Panama Pacific Exposition, 1913 February (Box 59, Folder 175)
    - Tahoe, undated (Box 59, Folder 176)
    - "The Tale of the Lost Kankakee", 1891 May (Box 59, Folder 177)
    - "Tamalpais as a National Park", 1903 September (Box 59, Folder 178)
    - Tamalpais Center Women's Club statement, 1927 June (Box 59, Folder 178)
    - "The Tariff", 1913 April (Box 59, Folder 179)
    - "Concerning Teachers", 1920 April (Box 59, Folder 179)
    - "To the Voters of Marin County", undated (Box 59, Folder 180)
    - "A Toothless Saw", 1906 Dec, 1907 April (Box 59, Folder 181)
      See also: box 57, folder 93
    - University Club smoker, 1912 (Box 59, Folder 181)
    - "Views of an Independent", 1914 March (Box 59, Folder 182)
    - "Vox Clamantis in Deserto", 1891 May (Box 59, Folder 183)
    - War, 1915 March (Box 59, Folder 184)
    - "The War and America", 1915 May (Box 59, Folder 185)